<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="45"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Dialysis Discovery





                                                                             grade 10


































































                                          Building Dialysis Device (SDGs)]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[All rights reserved  no part of this book may be reproduced,
                                stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted in any form or by
                                any means, electronic, mechanical, photocopying, recording or
                                otherwise, without prior written permission of the publishers.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[How to use this book?
             How to use this book?









                           This book is designed to captivate students through
                           storytelling, immersing them in real-world problems and
                           scenarios.


                           It provides a dynamic learning experience that merges
                           imagination with practical application, all while aligning
                           with STEAM (Science, Technology, Engineering, Arts, and
                           Mathematics) education principles.

                           And the project aligns with several Sustainable
                           Development Goals (SDGs), including:

                              SDG 3: Good Health and Well-being: By addressing the critical
                              healthcare issue of kidney failure and providing a potential solution,
                              the project directly contributes to improving global health.

                              SDG 9: Industry, Innovation, and Infrastructure: The project fosters
                              innovation and technological advancement by encouraging students
                              to design and develop a complex medical device, contributing to
                              infrastructure development in healthcare.

                              SDG 4: Quality Education: The project promotes STEM education and
                              critical thinking skills, preparing students for future careers and
                              contributing to the overall quality of education.

                              SDG 12: Responsible Consumption and Production: By considering
                              energy e ciency and sustainability in the design and development of
                              the device, the project aligns with responsible consumption and
                              production principles.

                              SDG 10: Reduced Inequalities: By aiming to provide accessible dialysis
                              treatment, the project contributes to reducing health disparities and
                              promoting equity.







                 1.        Stepping Stone:



                Where we merge your existing knowledge

                with exciting new discoveries.









                                                           A]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[2.     Inquiry-based learning !










                                  Think:

                                  In this section, students will brainstorm and explore possible
                                  solutions to speci c problems. This encourages critical
                                  thinking and creativity as they consider various approaches.





                Explore:

                Here, students will dive deeper into the topic. They will engage
                with curated videos, articles, educational games, and hands-on
                experiments to broaden their understanding and spark curiosity.




                                  Do it:

                                  It’s part of the explore, students will undertake hands-on
                                  projects where they will design, build, and test their own
                                  creations. They will apply scienti c principles, use technology
                                  and engineering skills, explore artistic concepts, and utilize
                                  mathematical reasoning.









                 3.    Problem-based learning:



                Introducing the problem:
                Students will join a journey to tackle real-world environmental challenges. Through
                hands-on activities and engaging tasks, they will apply their knowledge and skills to
                discover innovative solutions.



                Apply the Engineering Design Process (EDP):

                Students will use a structured approach to de ne problems, conduct research, generate
                ideas, prototype solutions, test , evaluate, and re ne their designs.








                                                           B]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[4.     Project-based learning



                Team Up:

                Students collaborate with peers to brainstorm, share ideas, and develop innovative
                solutions, enhancing communication, critical thinking, and teamwork.


                DIY Projects:

                Students tap into their creativity with hands-on projects that build technical skills and
                deepen their understanding of STEAM principles through experimentation and
                exploration.





                 5.     Case Studies




                This book also includes a Case Study section where students work to solve speci c
                problems.

                Each case study presents a real-world scenario that challenges students to apply
                their knowledge, think critically, and develop practical solutions.

                Through these case studies, students gain insight into how STEAM concepts are used
                to address real-life issues, fostering a deeper understanding and connection to the
                material.








                 6.     Assessment Exercises:

                        These are divided into three categories to ensure
                        comprehensive learning and mastery.


                Focus:                         Practice:                        Challenge:

                Tests student's                Provides opportunities for       Encourages deeper
                memorization and               students to apply what           thinking and creativity,
                understanding, ensuring        they've learned, building        pushing students to
                they grasp the                 con dence in their skills.       innovate and create new
                foundational concepts.                                          solutions.
















                                                           C]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Meet Your STEAM Bots!
            Meet Your STEAM Bots!








             Sparky Bot


                Sparky Bot helps you summarize key concepts
                and essential information. It guide, provides
                recaps, highlights important points, and o ers
                helpful hints and de nitions, ensuring you grasp
                everything clearly.





                                              Einstein Bot



                                                   Einstein Bot is your go-to for mastering
                                                   math and science. Named after the famous
                                                   physicist, it explains complex equations and
                                                   scienti c rules in an easy-to-understand
                                                   way. Whether it's algebra, physics, or
                                                   chemistry, Einstein Bot is like having a
                                                   mini-tutor at your  ngertips.






             Lab Bot


                Lab Bot is your guide for hands-on experiments.
                It o ers step-by-step instructions, safety tips, and
                troubleshooting advice for lab activities. Lab Bot
                ensures your experiments are smooth and successful,
                making science both fun and educational.






             Now I can…


                This section is designed to help you measure your progress and achievements.
                Enjoy your exploration and learning journey through this STEAM book!










                                                           D]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Theme: Building Dialysis Device                                             Index




                UNIT 01    [Beginner]
                                                                                                PAGE

                  week        Chapter 01: Design Domain
                       01          Lesson 01: Case Scenario.
                                   Lesson 02: Engineering design process.




                  week             Lesson 03: Building Dialysis Device.
                      02


                  week             Lesson 04: Kidney Model.
                      03




                  week        Chapter 02: Mechanics Domain.
                      04           Lesson 01: Fluids Viscosity.





                  week        Chapter 03: Electricity Domain.
                      05           Lesson 01: Automate Your Filter.








                UNIT 02     [Intermediate]
                                                                                                PAGE
                  week        Chapter 01: Design Domain
                      06
                                   Lesson 01: Dialysis Machine.




                  week        Chapter 02: Robotics Domain.
                      07
                                   Lesson 01: Fluids temperature sensor.






                UNIT 03     [Advanced]
                                                                                                PAGE

                  week        Chapter 01: Programing Domain.
                      08           Lesson 01: Dynamic Dialysis Website.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[UNIT 01        [ Beginner ]                                                LESSON 01

                  Chapter 01 : Design Domain.                                           Case Scenario.







               Designing a Portable Dialysis Machine


                   Introduction

                   Hospitals are facing a critical shortage of kidney  ltration devices,
                   directly impacting patient care and endangering the lives of those
                   with kidney failure. Dialysis is essential for  ltering waste from the
                   blood when the kidneys fail, and without su cient machines, patient
                   treatment is delayed. As biomedical engineers of the future, you will
                   tackle this challenge by designing a portable dialysis device that could
                   be used both in hospitals and at home. This project combines biology,
                   3D design, mechanics, electricity, and programming to create a
                   real-world solution.



                   Mission

                   Your mission is to design a portable, e cient, and safe dialysis
                   machine that can address the shortage of kidney  ltration devices.
                   The goal is to build a functional prototype that can be tested, and
                   potentially deployed, to improve patient access to life-saving
                   treatments.



                   Scenario Context

                   Who: Biomedical engineers, hospitals, patients, and healthcare
                   providers.
                   What: Hospitals need a portable, reliable dialysis machine to mitigate
                   the shortage of kidney  ltration devices.
                   Where: The machine will be used in both hospital settings and
                   potentially for home use.
                   When: The need for dialysis devices is urgent, and the project must be
                   completed as soon as possible to meet this demand.
                   Why: Dialysis is vital for patients with kidney failure, and the shortage
                   of devices puts patients at risk.


                   This project focuses on developing a practical solution to this problem.













                                                          03]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Driving Question

                 How can we design a portable, safe, and e cient dialysis machine
                 that can help solve the shortage of kidney  ltration devices in
                 hospitals and homes?

                 Objectives/Goals


                 By the end of this project, you will:
                 1.  Identify and label major organs of the urinary system (kidneys, ureters, bladder, urethra)
                     on a diagram.
                 2.  Articulate the primary functions of the urinary system: blood  ltration, urine production,
                     regulation of  uid and electrolyte balance.
                 3.  Use Tinkercad to create a 3D model of a kidney, applying principles of proportion, scale,
                     and symmetry.
                 4.  Understand the concept of  uid viscosity and control  ow rates in dialysis lines.

                 5.  Investigate materials used in dialysis (e.g., dialysate solutions) and how they impact the
                     process
                 6.  Add a water pump to the  ltration system and manage the power system for portable
                     dialysis.
                 7.  Break down complex components into simpler parts for design and digital assembly.

                 8.  Use Arduino to control a water pump and simulate the speed of blood dialysis, using PWM
                     to adjust  ow rates.

                 9.  Create an interactive website explaining the dialysis machine using HTML, CSS, and
                     JavaScript.


                 Your Challenge

                 By the end of this project, you’ll have:

                   Designed a 3D model and physical prototype of a portable dialysis machine using Tinkercad
                   and Arduino, simulating the blood  ltration process.

                   Understood the biological importance of your design by studying the urinary system and
                   ensuring your machine supports kidney function and dialysis processes.

                   Implemented  uid  ow control by programming an Arduino to regulate  ow rates,
                   simulating the speed and e ciency of blood  ltration.

                   Created an interactive website that explains the design, components, and functionality of
                   your dialysis machine for healthcare professionals and users.
                   Presented your prototype and website to a panel of experts or peers, demonstrating how
                   your solution addresses the shortage of dialysis machines in healthcare.

                 Are you ready to build a co ee shop model that could become the next big thing in the food
                 and beverage industry? Let’s get started!










                                                         04]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[UNIT 01        [ Beginner ]                                               LESSON 02

                  Chapter 01 : Design Domain.                        Engineering Design Process.








                Name:        . ....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................
                Name:
                              . ....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................
                Project:         . .........................................................................................................................................................................................................................................
                Project:
                                 . .........................................................................................................................................................................................................................................




                Ask                                                Imagine
                                                                   Imagine
                 Ask
















                Improve                                            Plan
                                                                   Plan
                 Improve















                Create
                 Create
























                                                          05]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[UNIT 01        [ Beginner ]                                               LESSON 03

                  Chapter 01 : Design Domain.                             Building Dialysis Device.






                  Re ection



               What do you think a biomedical engineer role is?



               . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................
               . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................


               Discover more about what biomedical engineer do by
               watching this video:
               https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAhk8OLY0V8
                                                                               Scan Here!







                                                                   How can we design a portable, safe,
                                                                   and e cient dialysis machine that
                                                                   can help solve the shortage of kidney
                 let's                                              ltration devices in hospitals and
                 let's
                                                                   homes?
                                                                   . ............................................................................................................
              Think                                                . ............................................................................................................
               Think

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

























                                                         06]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Explore
               Explore










                  WATCH IT..



                                       Click on the link to learn about the parts of
                                       the urinary system and how it  lters the
                                       waste.
                                       https://youtu.be/dxecGD0m0Xc?si=-M1PssUw
                                       vZpnjPHK
                                                                                               Scan Here!




                   READ IT..



                 Click the link to learn more about how your kidneys work and
                 how urine is formed.

                 https://www.niddk.nih.gov/health-information/kidney-disease/
                 kidneys-how-they-work?utm_source=chatgpt.com
                                                                                               Scan Here!






                                    Understanding Body Waste and Kidney
                                    Filtration.




                  Part 1: Body Waste
                  What happens to food and water after your body uses the energy
                  and nutrients?


                  . .......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................
                  . .......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . .......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . .......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................













                                                          07]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Name three materials your body eliminates as waste and explain why
                  they need to be removed.


                    Material 1:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................
                           Why:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................


                    Material 2:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................
                           Why:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................


                    Material 3:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................
                           Why:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................




                  Why is it important for the body to remove waste?


                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................
                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................


                  What materials does your body keep after  ltration? Why are they
                  important?


                    Material 1:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................
                  Importance:     . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................


                    Material 2:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................
                  Importance:     . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................



                    Material 3:   . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................
                  Importance:     . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................






























                                                         08]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Imagine you are designing a kidney  lter. What properties would it need
                  to separate waste (like urea) from useful substances (like nutrients or
                  water)? Why?


                  . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . .....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  How do you think the structure of the kidney helps it perform its
                   ltering role?

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................


                  Describe what happens if the kidneys are unable to perform their
                  function.

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ......................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................



























                                                         09]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Assessment Exercise









                          Focus
                          Focus






              Complete the blanks to label the parts of the urinary system.
              https://wordwall.net/resource/29599276/urinary-system-labeling
                                                                                               Scan Here!









                          Practice
                          Practice






               Design a poster or
               presentation to raise
               awareness about the
               urinary system.








































                                                          10]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[UNIT 01       [ Beginner ]                                               LESSON 04

                  Chapter 01 : Design Domain.                                           Kidney Model.






               Stepping Stone:
               Stepping Stone:



                 You neet to know…                               You will be able to…


                         How to use tinkercad for                       Demonstrate pro ciency in using
                         creating 3D designs.                           Tinkercad by creating a 3D
                                                                        model of a kidney, utilizing
                                                                        various design tools and
                                                                        features e ectively.
                                                                        prepare designs for 3D printing
                                                                        by exporting their models in
                                                                        the correct  le format using
                                                                        cura.





                                                                   How do the structure and arrangement
                                                                   of the kidneys help them e ectively
                                                                    lter waste and maintain balance in the
                                                                   body?
               let's
               let's

                                                                   . ...................................................................................................................
            Think                                                  . ...................................................................................................................
            Think


                                                                   . ...................................................................................................................

































                                                          11]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Explore
               Explore




















                Design the kidneys on
                Tinker cad.



















                  WATCH IT..





                                       Click on the link to learn how to use cura in
                                       adjusting your 3D designs for printing.
                                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cUVEoGfN45g
                                                                                               Scan Here!





























                                                          12]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Assessment Exercise









                          Focus
                          Focus





              What does Cura primarily help users do?

              A) Create 3D models from scratch.
              B) Convert digital models to printer instructions.
              C) Design software interfaces.
              D) Manufacture printer parts.


              Which of the following is a notable feature of Cura?

              A) Complex interface.
              B) Limited settings.
              C) User-friendly design.
              D) Expensive licensing.







                          Practice
                          Practice






              Adjust your design on cura
              and print it on the 3D printer.






























                                                          13]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Return back to the EDP paper and
                                        add this to the plan part.














                    NOW I CAN..




                     Prepare designs for 3D printing by exporting their models in the correct
                      le format using cura.
                     Demonstrate pro ciency in using Tinkercad by creating a 3D model of a
                     kidney, utilizing various design tools and features e ectively.

























































                                                          14]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[UNIT 01        [ Beginner ]                                               LESSON 01

                   Chapter 02 : Mechanical domain.                                    Fluids Viscosity.






               Stepping Stone:
               Stepping Stone:



                 You neet to know…                               You will be able to…


                         How kidneys  lter waste,                       Testing the viscosity of blood
                         regulate  uids, and maintain                   and water, along with
                         homeostasis.                                   controlling  ow rates in dialysis
                                                                        lines.

                                                                        Understanding what materials
                                                                        are added during the process
                                                                        and how this impacts dialysis
                                                                        machine performance.

                                                                        Preventing blockages in the lines
                                                                        by improving mechanical
                                                                        arrangements.

                                                                        Recognise Allmed Filter and
                                                                        understand its function.







                                                                   Click the link, explore the cell membrane
                                                                   simulation, and respond to the following
                                                                   question.
               let's                                               https://lab.concord.org/
               let's
                                                                   embeddable.html#inter
                                                                   actives/sam/diffusion/
            Think                                                  4-semipermeable.json         Scan Here!
            Think


                                                                   How does the size of the trace
                                                                   molecule compare to the size of the
                                                                   pores in the membrane? What would
                                                                   happen if the trace molecules were
                                                                   larger than the pores?


                                                                   . ...................................................................................................................

                                                                   . ...................................................................................................................

                                                                   . ...................................................................................................................






                                                          15]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Predict what would happen if the concentration of trace
               molecules on one side of the membrane was higher than the
               other side.



               . .............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . .............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               How could you use this model to explain the concept of
               selective permeability?


               . .............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . .............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................






             Explore
             Explore








                                  Give the students di erent materials to test the

                                  best materials for creating a Semipermeable
                                  Membrane, such as pieces of fabric, pieces of paper,
                                  pieces of mesh, and co ee  lter paper to see which
                                  will  lter the water better.



































                                                          16]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Semipermeable Membranes Worksheet




             The Problem
             You are part of an engineering team for a biomedical engineering
             company that is challenged to create the most innovative
             prototype to demonstrate the concept of permeability. You may
             use any of the materials provided at the front table.




             Constraints
             Use only three of the materials listed below. Materials are
             available on a “ rst come,  rst served” basis.








                        sugar cubes        newspaper         copy paper           mesh




                         cardboard         Co ee  lter paper towels               fabric









             Research Notes, Ideas, Questions…





































                                                          17]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Describe “semipermeable” below. Use words and/or a diagram.

























             Brainstorm
             Below, draw your group's idea of what you can make for a
             semipermeable membrane prototype.
             In your drawing, indicate what materials you are using.



















             Build
             Construct your prototype and make a drawing of your  nal
             prototype below.




























                                                          18]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Test
             Record your  ndings in the table below. Feel free to insert
             photos/drawings of your progress.




                  Test Criteria                     Trial 1       Trial 2        Trial 3       Trial 4


                  Drops of water to get
                  through the membrane.

                  Seconds it takes to move
                  through the membrane.





             Redesign
             How will you redesign your prototype? Answer the questions
             below.




                        What will you keep?                            What will you change?
















































                                                          19]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Make a drawing of your redesigned prototype.







































             Retest Revised Design

             Record your  ndings in the table
             below. Feel free to insert
             photos/drawings of your
             progress.











                 Test Criteria                     Trial 1        Trial 2       Trial 3        Trial 4


                 Drops of water to get
                 through the membrane.

                 Seconds it takes to move
                 through the membrane.












                                                          20]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Final Presentation
             Make a drawing of your  nal prototype design. Explain the
             elements of your prototype.





































             Analysis
             Answer the questions below.

             1.  Compare your design to the designs of other groups.

                 How are they similar? How are they di erent?


                 . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                 . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                 . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

             2.  Which materials worked the best? Consider all designs.



                 . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                 . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                 . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................











                                                          21]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[3.  As a class, work together to design the best prototype with
                 each group contributing ideas and elements to the new

                 prototype. Make a drawing that includes an explanation of the
                 elements.



















             4.  Test the new class prototype
                 design and record your
                  ndings below.















                 Test Criteria                     Trial 1        Trial 2       Trial 3        Trial 4


                 Drops of water to get
                 through the membrane.

                 Seconds it takes to move
                 through the membrane.




             5.  Conclusions:






















                                                         22]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[WATCH IT..






                                       Click on the link to explore how dialysis works.
                                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SgBMoCArNak

                                                                                               Scan Here!




                   READ IT..




                   Read the article to learn about, how a dialysis
                   machine works.
                   https://www.bbc.co.uk/bitesize/guides/zgh2xsg/revision/5
                                                                                               Scan Here!





                                                   An Allmed Filter is a high-quality  lter used in dialysis
                                                   machines. Its job is to clean the blood by separating
                                                   harmful substances from the useful parts of the blood.
                                                   It ensures that only clean and safe  uid passes back
                                                   into the patient’s body.
                                                   1.  Filtering Waste: The  lter removes harmful
                                                      substances like urea and toxins, which the
                                                      kidneys usually remove.

                                                   2.  Letting Useful Substances Stay: It allows
                                                      important parts of the blood, such as proteins
                                                      and blood cells, to stay in the bloodstream.

                                                   3.  Safety: Made from safe materials, Allmed Filters
                                                      work without causing harm to the blood or the
                                                      patient.



              4.  Durability: Dialysis can last for hours, and the
                 lter must work perfectly the entire time. Allmed
                Filters are reliable and don’t break down easily.

              5.  Clean and Pure: These  lters make sure that the
                process is sterile, meaning no germs or harmful
                particles get into the blood.











                                                          23]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Assessment Exercise










                          Practice
                          Practice





               What do you think viscosity means?


               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................


                 Fill the three containers with honey, water, and vegetable oil,
                 respectively.
                 Place a small ball or marble at the top of each container.
                 Time how long it takes for the ball to reach the bottom of each
                 container.
                 Discuss the results and explain how viscosity a ects the speed of the
                 ball.

               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  Heat one of the containers of water
                  on a hot plate while cooling another in
                  an ice bath.
                  Use thermometers to measure the
                  temperature of both containers.
                  Repeat the ball race experiment with
                  the heated and cooled water.
                  Discuss how temperature a ects
                  viscosity and the speed of the ball.


               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

               . ..................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................











                                                          24]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Viscosity is a key factor in the dialysis process, where
                                                    blood passes through narrow tubes in the machine.

                                                    Fluid Flow in Dialysis:
                                                    In the dialysis machine, blood  ows through tubing
                                                    while a dialysate (a  uid used to remove waste)  ows
                                                    on the other side of a semi-permeable membrane.
                                                    High blood viscosity can slow down the  ow, just like
                                                    the ball moves slower in honey compared to water.

                                                    Temperature's E ect on Viscosity:
                                                    Heating or cooling  uids in the experiment
                                                    demonstrates how temperature in uences viscosity.
                                                    Similarly, dialysis e ciency can depend on maintaining
                                                    optimal blood temperature for smooth  ow.

                                                    Blockages and Maintenance:
                                                    If blood is too viscous, it may increase the risk of
                                                    blockages in dialysis tubing. Understanding viscosity
                                                    helps in designing better systems and improving  uid
                                                     ow management.









                          Focus
                          Focus




              How does temperature a ect the e ciency of dialysis?

              A) Higher temperatures increase the rate of  ltration.
              B) Lower temperatures increase the rate of  ltration.
              C) Temperature has no e ect on  ltration.
              D) Temperature a ects  ltration only in certain conditions.



              What is the relationship between viscosity and the rate of  ltration in
              dialysis?

              A) Higher viscosity leads to a faster  ltration rate.
              B) Lower viscosity leads to a faster  ltration rate.
              C) Viscosity does not a ect  ltration rate.
              D) Viscosity and  ltration rate are inversely proportional.
















                                                          25]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Return back to the EDP paper and
                                        add this to the plan part.












                     NOW I CAN..




                      Testing the viscosity of blood and water, along with controlling  ow
                      rates in dialysis lines.


                      Preventing blockages in the lines by improving mechanical
                      arrangements.


                      Understanding what materials are added during the process and how
                      this impacts dialysis machine performance.

                      Recognise Allmed Filter and understand its function.

















































                                                         26]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[UNIT 01        [ Beginner ]                                               LESSON 01

                   Chapter 03 : Electricity domain.                            Automate your  lter.






               Stepping Stone:
               Stepping Stone:



                 You neet to know…                               You will be able to…


                                                                        Test and assemble circuits for
                         Water pump and its function.
                                                                        monitoring critical functions like
                                                                        blood  ow.
                         How to make electric circuit
                         using water pump.
                                                                        Describe the biological
                                                                         ltration process of the
                                                                        kidneys and compare it to the
                                                                        mechanical  ltration process
                                                                        of the water pump,
                                                                        highlighting similarities and
                                                                        di erences.






                                                                   How can we power your
               let's                                                ltration system?
               let's


            Think                                                  . ...................................................................................................................
            Think

                                                                   . ...................................................................................................................







              Explore
              Explore










                                    Add a water pump to your  ltration system
                                    with motor drive.










                                                          27]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Assessment Exercise









                          Focus
                          Focus



              How can the  ow rate of water in a dialysis system be measured?

              A) By counting the number of pumps used.
              B) By timing how long it takes to  ll a known volume of water.
              C) By measuring the temperature of the water.
              D) By checking the color of the water.

              What is the primary function of the water pump in a dialysis system?

              A) To  lter impurities from the blood.
              B) To circulate dialysate and blood through the dialyzer.
              C) To store excess water.
              D) To cool the dialysis machine.





                          Practice
                          Practice



              Work in pairs to compare the biological  ltration process of the kidneys and
              the mechanical  ltration process of the water pump, highlighting
              similarities and di erences.







                                      Return back to the EDP paper and
                                      add this to the plan part.








                    NOW I CAN..



                     Describe the biological  ltration process of the kidneys and compare it
                     to the mechanical  ltration process of the water pump, highlighting
                     similarities and di erences.






                                                         28]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[UNIT 02         [ Intermediate  ]                                          LESSON 01
                  Chapter 01 : Design domain.                                       Dialysis Machine.







               Stepping Stone:
               Stepping Stone:



                 You neet to know…                               You will be able to…


                                                                        Use blender to create 3D models of
                         3D design and compatible  le                   basic components of a dialysis machine.
                         formats for CNC printing.







                                                                   How can we design a portable,
                                                                   safe, and e cient dialysis
               let's                                               machine that can help solve the
               let's
                                                                   shortage of kidney  ltration
                                                                   devices in hospitals and homes?

            Think                                                  . ............................................................................................................
            Think

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................





              Explore
              Explore










                                    Explore the Overview of the interface and tools
                                    of blender and create your  rst 3D design.





                   Follow the video:

                   https://youtu.be/B0J27sf9N1Y?si=yiWYyT6xAI5YinDE
                                                                                               Scan Here!






                                                         28]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[WATCH IT..



                                       Before creating the dialysis machine, you need
                                       to think as product designer, click on the link to
                                       learn more about Characteristics of a design
                                       engineer.
                                       https://youtu.be/SD6d8Em8q5A?si=zikUKqlGqdBWJctd
                                                                                               Scan Here!






               Assessment Exercise








                          Practice
                          Practice




              Design dialysis system parts using blinder and print it on the CNC.








                                      Return back to the EDP paper and
                                      add this to the plan part.








                SHOWCASE



                  Assemble your dialysis device and add the  lter, blood lines to it.





                    NOW I CAN..




                     Use blender to create 3D models of basic components of a dialysis
                     machine.







                                                         28]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[UNIT 02         [ Intermediate  ]                                          LESSON 01
                  Chapter 02 : Robotics domain.                       Fluids Temperature Sensor.







               Stepping Stone:
               Stepping Stone:



                 You neet to know…                               You will be able to…


                                                                        Add Arduino to the water pump and
                         Basics of Arduino Programming.
                                                                        make a code to control the speed of
                                                                        blood dialysis and how it will a ect the
                                                                        health.
                         Electronic Components and
                         Circuits.
                                                                        Add liquid temperature sensor
                                                                        (DS18b20) to measure the temperature
                         Purpose, process, and the                      of the blood.
                         importance of regulating blood
                          ow and temperature.                           Investigate how altering the blood  ow
                                                                        rate (dialysis speed) can impact patient
                                                                        health, understanding the dangers of
                                                                        incorrect  ow rates in dialysis
                                                                        processes.








                                                                   How can we check the blood
                                                                   temperature in a dialysis
               let's                                               machine?
               let's
                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

            Think                                                  . ............................................................................................................
            Think
                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................
























                                                         28]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Explore
               Explore












                                    Connect the DS18B20 Sensor circuit with Arduino.






                  Write the Code:


                  Open the Arduino IDE and
                  upload the following code to

                  the Arduino board:
























































                                                          12]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[You have 3 cups labelled.



                 Cup 1: Hot water
                 Cup 2: Cold water (with ice, if available)

                 Cup 3: Room temperature water





                  Immerse the DS18B20 sensor into Cup 1 (Hot Water) and wait for the reading to
                  stabilize.

                  Record the temperature shown on the Serial Monitor or LCD.

                  Repeat the process with Cup 2 (Cold Water) and Cup 3 (Room Temperature Water).

                  Use a thermometer to measure the temperature of each cup and record it for
                  comparison.


                    Cup                      DS18B20 Temperature (°C)   Thermometer Temperature (°C)

                    Hot Water

                    Cold Water

                    Room Temperature



                  How accurate were the DS18B20 readings compared to the thermometer?

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  Which cup had the highest temperature? The lowest?

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  Which cup had the highest temperature? The lowest?

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  What are some real-world applications for temperature sensors like the DS18B20?

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................

                  . ............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................







                                                          12]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[WATCH IT..





                                       Click on the link to learn more about DS18B20
                                       (liquid temperature sensor).
                                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hIkUQZuaTE4

                                                                                               Scan Here!






               Assessment Exercise









                          Focus
                          Focus



              What is the primary advantage of using a DS18B20 sensor in wet
              environments?
              A) Low cost.
              B) Small size.
              C) Waterproof design.
              D) High temperature range.

              How many wires are required for connecting the DS18B20 to a
              microprocessor?
              A) One.
              B) Two.
              C) Three.
              D) Four.


























                                                          12]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Practice
                          Practice




              Integrate this circuit with a water pump and a motor driver, and include
              an LCD to display the data. Write the code to control the pump's speed and
              monitor the blood's temperature.














































































                                                          12]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Return back to the EDP paper and
                                        add this to the plan part.












                     NOW I CAN..




                      Connect and code a temperature sensor to monitor the temperature of
                      blood-like  uid in real-time.


                      Add temperature sensor to measure the temperature of the blood.

                      Investigate how altering the blood  ow rate (dialysis speed) can
                      impact patient health, understanding the dangers of incorrect  ow
                      rates in dialysis processes.

                      Add Arduino to the water pump and make a code to control the speed
                      of blood dialysis and how it will a ect the health.















































                                                          12]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[UNIT 03         [ Advanced ]                                               LESSON 01

                  Chapter 01 : Web development domain.                        Dynamic dialysis website.






               Stepping Stone:
               Stepping Stone:



                 You neet to know…                               You will be able to…


                         The basic structure of an HTML                 Emphasize the importance of making
                         document, including tags.                      the website accessible to all users,
                                                                        including those with disabilities.
                         The purpose of CSS and how it works
                         with HTML.
                                                                        Dynamically update webpage content
                                                                        based on user inputs or system status.
                         CSS layout techniques ( exbox,
                         grid, and media  queries).

                         Include JavaScript in an HTML  le.









                                                                   How can we create an
                                                                   interactive website that
                                                                   e ectively educates users about
               let's                                               the components and functions of
               let's
                                                                   a dialysis machine? What
                                                                   features could you include in it?
            Think                                                  . ............................................................................................................
            Think


                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................


















                                                          12]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Explore
               Explore











                  WATCH IT..




                                       Follow the link to explore the 7 essential steps
                                       for creating a website
                                       https://youtu.be/F4fbwKV9dBU?si=-Q7-tiPyO-VsfCTn
                                                                                               Scan Here!


                                       Learn about how to create dynamic website
                                       using java script (watch from min 6)
                                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDzB2hI0esQ


                                                                                               Scan Here!







                                    Follow the 7 steps of website creation learned
                                    earlier and design a professional website for
                                    your dialysis machine.



              The website should be developed using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
              and must include the following features:




              Navigation Menu:

              Create a menu bar with links to the following pages:
                 Home.
                 Details.
                 Features.
                 Contact Us.













                                                          12]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Dynamic Content:

              Use JavaScript to update the content of the website dynamically
              when users click on navigation links, instead of reloading the
              page.




              Content Organization:

              Ensure each page contains relevant information:
                 Home: Introduce your dialysis machine and its purpose.
                 Details: Provide technical details and speci cations.
                 Features: Highlight the unique features of your product.
                 Contact Us: Include a form for users to reach out with their
                 queries (e.g., name, email, and message).






























































                                                          12]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Return back to the EDP paper and
                                        add this to the plan part.












                     NOW I CAN..




                      Emphasize the importance of making the website accessible to all
                      users, including those with disabilities.


                      Dynamically update webpage content based on user inputs or system
                      status


























































                                                          12]]></page></pages></Search>