<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="13"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Lesson Overview:

               This lesson introduces uppercase letters (B, F, O, G) is to familiarize students with the visual form
               of capital letters and help them understand their proper use in writing. This foundation
               prepares students for recognizing uppercase letters in reading and using them correctly in
               sentence structure, such as at the beginning of names or sentences. It also reinforces their
               understanding of letter-sound correspondence, enabling early literacy skills such as recognizing
               words and forming basic sentences.

               Learning Objectives:

               1. Students will accurately recognize and identify the uppercase letters B, F, O, and G.

               2. Students will be able to spell simple words containing the uppercase letters B, F, O, and G.

               3. Students will be able to read simple words containing the uppercase letters B, F, O, and G.




               Materials:

               General:

                   ● Timer/Bell
                   ● Manipulative
                   ● Mind Buzz nomenclature cards
                   ● Mind Buzz Student Book






               Presentation (Daily - 7 minutes):

               •       PowerPoint presentation.




               Objective:

               By the end of the week, students will identify the uppercase letters B, F, O, and G and students
               will spell and read simple words containing the uppercase letters B, F, O, and G.



               Group Instruction:

                   ● Begin with the PowerPoint presentation.
                   ● Show picture cards, and ask students to say the words.

               Individual Support:]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[● Monitor each student, and provide individual assistance if needed.
                   ● Encourage shy students to build confidence by praising their efforts and allowing them
                       to contribute in ways that feel comfortable.

                   Applying Multiple Intelligence Differentiation

                   ● Visual Learners: Benefit from picture cards.
                   ● Auditory Learners: participate actively in listening to and discussing spoken instructions.
                   ● Kinesthetic Learners: Hands- on activities.










               Station Activities (Day 1 to 3)










               Station 1: Sorting Strips into Cups (uppercase to lowercase)

               Objective:

               By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly identify and differentiate between the
               uppercase letters B, F, O, and G during assessment activities. The learning process will involve
               engaging, age-appropriate materials and interactive methods to support letter recognition and
               understanding.

               Materials:

                   ● Individual letter strips with B, F, O, and G letters, 4 cups labeled with b, f, o, and g.

               Activity:

                   ● Students sort individual letter strips with the target letter into the corresponding cups.



               Steps:


                   1. Lay out the cups over the workspace.
                   2. Pick up a strip, identify the letter, and place it in the correct cup.
                   3. Pass the strips to the next student.
                   4. Teacher observes and offers help when needed.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Group Instruction:

                   ● Model the activity first.
                   ● Engage students by asking questions like, "Can you name this letter?" or "What is this
                       letter?"

               Individual Support:

                   ● Assist students who struggle with identifying letters.
                   ● Offer positive reinforcement to build confidence.


                       Types of Learners:
                       Visual Learners: Observe the letter strips and cups.
                       Auditory Learners: Listen to the letters being identified.
                       Kinesthetic Learners: Actively engage in sorting the strips.



               SMART Objective:

                   ● By the end of the session, students will accurately sort all the letter strips into the
                       correct cups.








               Station 2: Uppercase-Lowercase Vocabulary Puzzle

               Objective


                By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly identify and match uppercase letters,
               corresponding vocabulary words, and their lowercase counterparts during assessment activities.
               This interactive puzzle game will support letter recognition and vocabulary development
               through engaging, hands-on learning.


               Materials:


               Puzzle pieces for each letter (B, F, O, G):

                   1. Part 1: Uppercase letter (e.g., "B").
                   2. Part 2: Vocabulary word starting with the letter (e.g., "Bed")
                   3. Part 3: Lowercase letter (e.g., "b").

               Activity:]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[● Students match each set of puzzle pieces to correctly connect the uppercase letter,
                       corresponding vocabulary word, and lowercase letter.


               Steps:

                   1. Lay out all puzzle pieces over the workspace.
                   2. Have the students start by selecting an uppercase letter piece.
                   3. Encourage the students to find the vocabulary word that matches the letter (e.g., "B"
                       with "Bed").
                   4. Next, ask them to find the corresponding lowercase letter piece (e.g., "B" with "Bed"
                       with "b")

                   5. Students connect all three pieces to complete the puzzle.
                   6. Repeat with the next letter until all letters are matched correctly.


               Group Instruction:


                   ● Model how to find and match the puzzle pieces.
                   ● Ask guiding questions like “What word starts with this letter?” and “What does the
                       lowercase of this letter look like?”


               Individual Support:

                   ● Assist students who may struggle with matching the correct vocabulary word or
                       lowercase letter.
                   ● Provide encouragement and praise to help build confidence and reinforce learning.


               Types of Learners:

                   ● Visual Learners: Engage with the puzzle pieces visually.
                   ● Auditory Learners: Listen to the vocabulary word and letter name.
                   ● Kinesthetic Learners: Actively participate by handling and assembling the puzzle.

               SMART Objective:


                   ● By the end of the session, students will accurately match the puzzle pieces, correctly
                       connecting the uppercase letter, vocabulary word, and lowercase letter.









               Station 3: Star Game]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Objective: By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly identify the high-frequency
               words "am" and "and" during assessment activities and they will also revisit the previously
               learned words, ensuring reinforcement of past lessons. The Star Game will engage students in a
               hands-on activity where they practice word recognition by hiding identified words with a
               star-shaped cover.

               Materials:


                   ● Large word card with high-frequency words "am" "and" "I" &"can”.
                   ● Star-shaped covers that can be placed over the words on the large cards.

               Activity:


                   ● Students will take turns identifying a high-frequency word on a large card and then
                       covering it with a star-shaped cover.

               Steps:


                   1. Lay out the large word card face up on the workspace.
                   2. The student correctly identifies the word on the card by saying it aloud.
                   3. After identifying the word, the student places the star-shaped cover over the word,
                       hiding it from view.
                   4. The next student repeats the process.
                   5. Continue until all students have had a turn to identify and hide words.

               Group Instruction:


                   ● Demonstrate how to play the Star Game, showing how to identify the word and cover it
                       with the star.
                   ● Engage the group by asking questions like “Which word will you hide with the star?” to
                       reinforce identification before covering.

               Individual Support:


                   ● Assist students who may struggle with identifying the words.
                   ● Encourage correct identification and provide positive reinforcement to build confidence.

               Types of Learners:


                   ● Visual Learners: Observe the word card and the stars.
                   ● Auditory Learners: Listen to the words being identified aloud.
                   ● Kinesthetic Learners: Actively participate by handling the star and word card.


               SMART Objective:]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[● By the end of the session, students will accurately identify and hide the words using the
                       star cover, reinforcing their recognition of "am" and "and".













               Station 4: High-Frequency Words Memory Game


               Objective:
               By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly identify the high-frequency words
               "am" and "and" during assessment activities. They will also revisit the previously learned words,
               ensuring reinforcement of past lessons.

               Materials:
                   ● Word cards



               Activity:
               · Students will play a memory game where they match pairs of high-frequency word cards, using
                   color association to help identify and remember the words.
               Steps:

                   1. Lay out the word cards face down on the workspace.
                   2. Flip two cards to find matching pairs.
                   3. Start by turning over two cards and check if they match.
                   4. Continue until all pairs are found.
                   5. Students take turns flipping two cards to find pairs.
                   6. Use the card colors to help remember locations.

                   7. After all pairs are matched, review the words together.


               Group Instruction:
               · Play a round together to ensure all students understand the game.
               · Encourage teamwork and turn-taking during the game.

               · Ask guiding questions like “What color is this word?” and “Have we seen this word before?”
               Individual Support:
               · Assist students who may have difficulty remembering card positions.
               · Use strategies like repeating the words aloud to reinforce memory.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Station 5(optional): Letter Bingo

               Objective:

               By the end of the week, students will correctly identify and mark squares with the letters /B/,
               /F/, /O/, and /G/ during a 7-minute Bingo game session, reinforcing their ability to recognize
               and identify upper case letters.

               Materials:

                   ● Bingo cards with B, F, O, and G letters, calling cards, manipulatives for marking squares.
               Activity:

                   ● Students play Bingo, identifying and marking squares with the letters called out.


                       Steps:
               1. Choose a student to be the “caller.”

               2. Distribute bingo cards.

               3. Caller says the name of a letter.

               4. Students cover the corresponding letter on their cards.

               5. Play until all spaces are covered.




               Group Instruction:

                   ● Explain the rules clearly.
                   ● Demonstrate a few rounds before starting.
               Individual Support:

                   ● Help students who have difficulty keeping up.
                   ● Encourage peer support for struggling students.
               Applying Multiple Intelligence Differentiation

                   ● Visual Learners: See the bingo cards and markings.
                   ● Auditory Learners: Listen to the letter called out.
                   ● Kinesthetic Learners: Use manipulatives to mark the cards.
               SMART Objective:

                   ● Students will correctly identify and mark all the sounds called out.
               Station Activities (Day 4 &5)]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Station 1: Sorting Strips into Cups (uppercase to lowercase)

               Objective:

               By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly identify and differentiate between the
               uppercase letters B, F, O, and G during assessment activities. The learning process will involve
               engaging, age-appropriate materials and interactive methods to support letter recognition and
               understanding.

               Materials:

                   ● Individual letter strips with B, F, O, and G letters, 4 cups labeled with b, f, o, and g.

               Activity:

                   ● Students sort individual letter strips with the target letter into the corresponding cups.




               Steps:

                       1. Lay out the cups over the workspace.
                       2. Pick up a strip, identify the letter, and place it in the correct cup.
                       3. Pass the strips to the next student.
                       4. Teacher observes and offers help when needed.

               Group Instruction:

                   ● Model the activity first.
                   ● Engage students by asking questions like, "Can you name this letter?" or "What is this
                       letter?"

               Individual Support:

                   ● Assist students who struggle with identifying letters.
                   ● Offer positive reinforcement to build confidence.


                       Types of Learners:
                       Visual Learners: Observe the letter strips and cups.
                       Auditory Learners: Listen to the letters being identified.
                       Kinesthetic Learners: Actively engage in sorting the strips.



               SMART Objective:]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[● By the end of the session, students will accurately sort all the letter strips into the
                       correct cups.





               Station 2: Star Game

               Objective: By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly identify the high-frequency
               words "am" and "and" during assessment activities and they will also revisit the previously
               learned words, ensuring reinforcement of past lessons. The Star Game will engage students in a
               hands-on activity where they practice word recognition by hiding identified words with a
               star-shaped cover.

               Materials:


                   ● Large word card with high-frequency words "am" "and" "I" &"can”.
                   ● Star-shaped covers that can be placed over the words on the large cards.

               Activity:


                   ● Students will take turns identifying a high-frequency word on a large card and then
                       covering it with a star-shaped cover.

               Steps:


                       1. Lay out the large word card face up on the workspace.
                       2. The student correctly identifies the word on the card by saying it aloud.
                       3. After identifying the word, the student places the star-shaped cover over the word,
                          hiding it from view.
                       4. The next student repeats the process.
                       5. Continue until all students have had a turn to identify and hide words.


               Group Instruction:

                   ● Demonstrate how to play the Star Game, showing how to identify the word and cover it
                       with the star.
                   ● Engage the group by asking questions like “Which word will you hide with the star?” to
                       reinforce identification before covering.

               Individual Support:


                   ● Assist students who may struggle with identifying the words.
                   ● Encourage correct identification and provide positive reinforcement to build confidence.

               Types of Learners:]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[● Visual Learners: Observe the word card and the stars.
                   ● Auditory Learners: Listen to the words being identified aloud.
                   ● Kinesthetic Learners: Actively participate by handling the star and word card.


               SMART Objective:

                   ● By the end of the session, students will accurately identify and hide the words using the
                       star cover, reinforcing their recognition of "I" and "can".




















               Station 3: Unscrambling Sentences

               Objective: By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly unscramble simple
               sentences using word cards during assessment activities. This activity will reinforce sentence
               structure and word recognition through hands-on learning.

               Materials:


                   ● Sets of word cards with simple sentences.
                   ● Control cards showing the correct sentences for self-checking.

               Activity:


                   ● Students will unscramble the word cards to form a correct sentence, then check their
                       work using the control card.

               Steps:


                   1. Provide students with a set of scrambled word cards and a matching control card.
                   2. The student unscrambles the word cards to form a coherent sentence.
                   3. After forming the sentence, the student checks their work by comparing it to the control
                       card.
                   4. If the sentence matches the control card, the student moves on to the next set of
                       scrambled words.
                   5. If the sentence does not match, the student tries again until it is correct.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Group Instruction:


                   ● Demonstrate how to unscramble a sentence using the word cards, showing how to use
                       the control card as a guide
                   ● Engage students by asking questions like “What should come first in this sentence?” to
                       help them think about sentence structure.


               Individual Support:


                   ● Assist students who may have difficulty arranging the words in the correct order.
                   ● Encourage self-correction using the control card, and provide positive reinforcement to
                       build confidence.





               Types of Learners:


                   ● Visual Learners: See the word cards and control card.
                   ● Auditory Learners: Listen to the sentence being read aloud.
                   ● Kinesthetic Learners: Actively participate by arranging and rearranging the word cards.

               SMART Objective:


                   ● By the end of the session, students will accurately unscramble the sentences, correctly
                       using the control card to verify their work.












               Station 4: Match pictures to sentences

               Objective: By the end of the week, students will be able to correctly match pictures to sentences
               during assessment activities. The Picture Match Game will engage students in a hands-on
               activity where they practice associating images with corresponding sentences.

               Materials:


                   ● Picture cards with various images.
                   ● Sentence cards that correspond to the pictures.


               Activity:]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[● Students will take turns selecting a picture card and finding the matching sentence card.

               Steps:


                   1. Lay out the picture cards and sentence cards face up on the workspace.
                   2. The student selects a picture card and reads the sentence cards to find the matching
                       sentence.
                   3. Once a match is found, the student places the sentence card next to the corresponding
                       picture card.
                   4. The next student repeats the process.
                   5. Continue until all pictures and sentences have been matched.


               Group Instruction:

                   ● Demonstrate how to play the Picture Match Game, showing how to select a picture and
                       find the corresponding sentence.
                   ● Engage the group by asking questions like “Which sentence matches this picture?” to
                       reinforce the reading and matching process.


               Individual Support:


                   ● Assist students who may struggle with reading or matching sentences.
                   ● Encourage correct matches and provide positive reinforcement to build confidence.


               Types of Learners:

                   ● Visual Learners: Observe the picture cards and sentence cards.
                   ● Auditory Learners: Listen to the sentences being read aloud.
                   ● Kinesthetic Learners: Actively engage by handling the picture cards and sentence cards.

               SMART Objective:


                   ● By the end of the session, students will accurately match pictures to sentences,
                       reinforcing their ability to connect visual images with written text.









               Mind buzz student book

               Objective:

               The last 10 minutes of the session on the fourth and fifth days will be allocated to answering
               exercises in the student book. These exercises will reinforce their ability to discriminate]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[between different initial sounds, which is crucial for early reading development, and help
               differentiate between the uppercase letters B, F, O, and G during assessment activities.]]></page></pages></Search>